[
  { 
    "question": "Shido!", 
    "answer":   "Note! (referee's call for slight penalty)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hansoku Make!",
    "answer":   "Loss by rule violation (referree's call)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hantei!",   
    "answer":   "Decision! (call by referee for judges' decision)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sono Mama!",   
    "answer":   "Don't move! (referee's call)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Yoshi!",   
    "answer":   "Continue! (referee's call)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Shizen Hontai",   
    "answer":   "Fundamental natural posture"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jigo Hontai",   
    "answer":   "Fundamental defensive posture"
  },
  {
    "question": "Harai/Barai",   
    "answer":   "Sweeping action done with the leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gari",   
    "answer":   "Reaping action done with the leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Gake/Kake",   
    "answer":   "Dashing action action done with the leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hane",   
    "answer":   "Springing action done with the leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nage",   
    "answer":   "Throw (noun)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Waza",   
    "answer":   "Technique(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Nage Waza",   
    "answer":   "Throwing Technique(s)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Te",   
    "answer":   "Hand"
  },
  {
    "question": "Te Waza",   
    "answer":   "Hand Techniques"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ashi",   
    "answer":   "Foot or leg"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ashi Waza",   
    "answer":   "Foot techniques"
  },
  {
    "question": "O",   
    "answer":   "Big or major"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ko",   
    "answer":   "Little or minor"
  },
  {
    "question": "Goshi/Koshi",   
    "answer":   "Waist or hip"
  },
  {
    "question": "Koshi Waza",   
    "answer":   "Waist or hip techniques"
  },
  {
    "question": "Soto",   
    "answer":   "Outside"
  },
  {
    "question": "Uchi",   
    "answer":   "Inside"
  },
  {
    "question": "Ki",   
    "answer":   "Internal force or spiritual energy"
  },
  {
    "question": "Kiai",   
    "answer":   "Shout to gather inner strength"
  }
]
